so I know a lot of us or at least uh
well some of us were trying to improve
product search using machine learning
and large language models and so is
Amazon so in our last talk today a and
braine are talking about how Amazon is
uh using LM and ml to improve product
search thank you
hi everyone thanks for staying around I
think this is the last session but good
news there are vultures for you for the
drinks later so um stay with us so I
think throughout the day we've seen that
machine learnings llms are integrating
the whole search pipeline or search life
cycle and the Next Generation product
search is a reality at this point now in
the session we'll cover how to build
these integration machine learnings llms
into your search engine and uh in our
use case we are using open search uh as
the search engine so uh my name is haif
and I am a Solutions architect at iws
focusing on open search and with me
today Prine hello everyone myself Prine
moan Prasad I'm an analytic specialist
with AWS for almost three and a half
years I'm focusing an Amazon open
service operational excellence with
customers thanks Pine
all right let's start with the basics
what is the life cycle of a
search in general we start with data
ingestion right in order to be able to
search that data um for the data
ingestion side we prepar the data by
enriching it using natural language
processing techniques computer vision
techniques to capture information from
the images for example um and then put
it in the right format in order to be
able to store it into your search engine
this case as we mentioned it is open
search now we have a search query coming
in the search query will go through the
same pre-processing step right first we
need to understand what is the intention
of the user on the web application right
and I think this was the main topic of
today how can we capture the most most
efficient way our user's intention so
the query in itself will go into
enrichment phase uh we can do query
expansion we can do um entity
recognition semantic understanding of
the query and this leads usually into
query
rewriting now uh we'll run the search
against the search engine the search
engine will takes care usually of uh
building the score of the documents
ranking the results and making sure that
you have the top uh most relevant
results at the top you render your
results to the front end of application
and need to make sure that also from the
web application side you display the
products in the right order let's say in
order to make it easier for your user to
click or capture the most relevant uh
document for
them now once we display the uh results
we would like to understand are these
results really relevant to our users
that are using the web application so we
capture the user signals we feed these
user signals into postprocessing step so
we train our ranking model everyone I
think today we spoke about uh ranking um
and um use that also as a feedback loop
to provide this information as a
contextual information for the next uh
queries
and here you do not only capture the
user signals you should also update with
your business requirements so we have
two personas that we need to take into
consideration now uh in this session uh
myself and Prine will go into each step
and we'll cover how you can build these
Integrations uh with open
search so somehow you're not still not
aware of open search and you missed the
first session it is an open- source
project that recently uh joined the
Linux
Foundation now from machine learning
perspective and uh llms so they usually
are whether self-hosted or you are using
managed Services right in whatever Cloud
um that that you are using and these ml
models can be used to generate
embeddings can we use as we mentioned
for NLB processing computer vision um
and also you have the
llms now at ingestion time wherever you
have text images usually you would
process this data outside of your search
engine and then you get the results and
store them into your search
engine now with open search you can use
injust
pipeline in order to get those documents
in row format and use the injust
pipeline inside open search within open
search to invoke the uh machine learning
services or your llm uh via a machine
learning
connector and use the processors that
are available let's say chunking
processor uh embed gener embedding
generation processor um enrichment
processor using your own machine
learning model and this will be in
invoked by the injust pipeline to
pre-process the data store them into
your open search and now at search time
the same process will go uh will will
will run so uh we can also process the
user query using search pipelines that
themselves they have uh processors that
will be run at search time um and uh
process your data for example for hybrid
search we have a combination izers
processes that will uh normalize this
course from your lexical search and uh
Vector
search and we'll uh cover some examples
later also even with llms you can build
your conversational search with an open
search in itself using the search
Pipeline and rug processor so if you
have time uh we hope we have a demo on
conversational search
here and then open search will render
the machine powered machine learning
powered results into your uh application
and this reduces the complexity of
managing any pipelines uh outside of
your search engine and also reduces the
complexity of having multiple components
uh and managing the multiple components
separately from your uh search engine
that usually reir engineering teams uh
and a lot of process to incorporate any
new ingestion uh flow
all right so on a high
level we have these four steps query
understanding query rewriting we
retrieve the documents and then we
rerank the results so um from my side so
I will start with the query
understanding query rewriting and Prine
will take it for document retrieval and
results
reranking now in order to understand our
query or Our users's intention we need
to understand what do we have in terms
of document first in order to match the
user request with our data
set and that's why query understanding
starts at ingestion time so let's say if
you have an image or we have a text we
can use object detection models to
capture what are the objects in our
images uh create labels um and if we
have a text we capture the entities here
um like for example what we have so we
have Bob ordered two sandwiches and
three ice creams uh comes today from a
store in Seattle so we have location we
have a person um and we have time entity
as well apologies I think here it's not
clear like the the colors uh but I'm
saying it outl so out loud so you can
understand what is the text in there
and here uh whether for image or the
text we have enriched our documents we
capture as much information as possible
from our document data set to add these
labels for the image for example we have
a description of the image we have the
color the category um and object and for
the text we have the entities as I
mentioned person quantity date location
Etc now whether you are using your own
trained machine learning model here like
for object detection or named entity
recognition you can use the uh machine
learning inference processor that uh
will be called at injust time within the
search pipeline to enrich your documents
and update your uh data set with an open
search once we understand our data once
we make sure that we have uh the enough
metadata about what we know will be able
to apply this understanding at query
time so the query
here is brown leather shoes for men
under
$50 which she the the first one um and
then we will have the query the query
here will make sure that we apply the
right filters based on the uh user
intention though so the user is looking
for a category of footware is they are
using uh or searching for a footware
that is under $50 so we'll apply filters
across the category price range gender
as a male color brown and if we have any
information related for example location
or time we'll add uh we'll be able to
add more filtering here and this can
come let's say uh implicitly if we have
enough information from the user like
what language are they using or or what
is their current location current time
Etc now if we take a popular e-commerce
website I think you
all knew what's what's the e-commerce so
this is
amazon.com and we apply the same query
brown leather shoes for men under
$50 now all the results that we got from
uh the e-commerce website they are
matching what we're looking for they are
shoes for men they are brown uh they are
leather and they are under $50 however
when we check for example description
here there is no information on the
price there is no formation of the
fabric of the of the shoes so here if we
go into details of this first shoes for
example we see that we had filters
applied against these
entities and this is done by first
capturing the entities as we mentioned
and then rewriting our query in order to
filter out as much as we can the most
relevant uh
documents this will help in reducing the
computational load and will help uh
retrieving or rewriting uh the the query
for the best matching with our user
intent now I mentioned about query re
writing and uh we can use large language
models to uh rewrite the queries you can
find J your large language models in
this case um and here we are using the
llm to write the same query that I was
talking about brown leather shoes for
men under $50 and put it into structured
format first the structured query allow
us to First capture the entities in the
uh user query and also it gives us
flexibility
about what type of filters do we apply
really do we should we go with a strict
must should we go with the
should like we have based on our
business requirement as as I mentioned
you have two personas you have the user
and you have your business users as well
so we should think here taking the
structured query generated from the llm
and apply those filters but rewrite them
into the best combination for our uh
business use case so here we apply a
mass for example we need to have a
description matching shoes and then we
filter out the category price gender
color Etc and Prine will show us later a
demo how this is H
built if you want to build it yourself
uh we provide the GitHub example here uh
by scanning the QR code to see how you
can do that so what we are doing in this
example is that we we are not training
or fine tuning the llms but we are
providing SC shots examples and we are
demonstrating how this structured query
helps us to rewrite our query uh to DSL
open search understandable query and you
can apply the same logic uh based on
your search engine uh query
language give you some time to scan the
QR codes if uh needed
I think we're good
yeah all right so there is no surprise
that invoking llms can be
expensive and everyone who
um experien it with with the llms can uh
can confirm this so
here we are using open search
as our caching store usually in order
for the caching we use exact matching
lexical to compare the queries with what
we have in terms of H golden query sets
for example but we can use also semantic
queries that hence the name semantic
cache meaning we'll start the query the
structured query the the original query
sorry and the structured query generated
by the llm into for example if you have
data into open search you can create
another index with an open search and
use it as a cache and here we'll store
the original query the structured query
and the embedding so whenever you have a
new query will run similarity search uh
against using Canon index to retrieve uh
if we have similar queries or not if we
have a match so we return the structural
query we write the query based on our
business use case if not we invoke the
llm to generate the structured
query so this does not only reduce the
llm cost but also reduces the latency
and from our experiment uh we reduced
the search latency from 3 seconds into
milliseconds so as a Solutions architect
we also provide best practices into how
to further reduce cost and improve your
performance first recommendation is
warming up your cash on a regular basis
this will depends on your um recency of
your data frequency of updating your uh
queries have seasonalities
Etc um warming up the cach will uh
improve the latency uh and that's one of
the best practices even when running
similarity search outside of caching uh
strategy also uh Delete the data that
you do not need delete the old data for
example that you know that users will
not be quing if let's say iPad 5 who
will add oh sorry like iPhone 5 who will
search for iPhone 5 now so delete the
cash as much as as you can and you can
use ISM andex State Management policies
in open search to automate uh the
deletion of your data based on the um
recency of your
data last option is uh you can check
also like you can build the same caching
uh mechanism using a framework with L
chain they have built in semantic cache
with uh open search that you can check
out now we covered query understanding
query rewriting think I'll give the mic
to Prine to show us how to build query
document retrieval with machine learning
uh
capabilities yeah thanks
haer okay so haer showed us like how
what are the machine learning and llm
innovations that you could do on the
query understanding and rewriting part
especially with open search so now let's
jump into the next phase of the uh
search life cycle which is a retrieval P
right and yeah today like as we covered
like all the past sessions most of us
know about the different types of
retrieval but just as a quick warm up we
will we will look at the quickly on the
different types of retrieval techniques
so first broadly we have two categories
right Spar retrieval and the D retrieval
and for The Spar retrieval we have the
algorithm such as bm25 or term frequency
inverse document frequency and have and
we have two two categories here lexical
search the basic keyword matching
technique and the other one is a neural
Spar search which is a machine learning
way of doing lexical search where you do
the term expansion and then you do the
basic lexical search and this expand
expanded terms you get it from the
neural SP models we'll have a we'll
we'll uh deep Dave on this particular
search later and then we have this Den
retrieval which is based upon K nearest
neighbor approach or the approximate
nearest neighbor approach and and here
is where you convert your documents and
queries into Vector representations and
for every query Vector you're going to
look for the nearest document vector and
then throw them as results and
the advantage here is that you you can I
mean you can convert your documents of
different modality into vectors and then
apply the same K and search and and then
we uh we just went through
this by multiple examples
today next we have hybrid search and
this is like Ensemble uh way of
combining multiple retrieval techniques
and then uh uh do do a do a sort of
hybrid retrieval where like say you want
to combine keyword search and also the
vector search and and then um uh do the
scoring separately normalize the scores
com combine the scores and then do the
reordering based upon your uh your new
combined scores right so this way you
can you can also have uh your keyword
search Techniques plus the vector search
techniques respected for a particular
query and then the last we have
conversational search which is the
retrieval augumented generative
uh approach from the large language
models basically you retrieve the
documents from any of the search tapes
here and then you send them as context
to the large language model along with
the original question and then you you
have your large language model to
generate the final answer so this is one
of the popular use case that we uh that
is used to build chat Bots we will see
like how to use it in open search uh to
build a conversational
search Okay so let's start with neural
Spar search having understood lexical
search like it's like basic will will
jump into the neural Spar search so
basically on the inje S say if you have
a document something like Apple products
are
expensive uh you're going to use the
inest pipeline like as haer explained
this inest pipeline is going to make it
easy for all the machine learning
Integrations right so this you're going
to use the injust pipel with sparse
encoding processor and this SP encoding
processor will be responsible for
converting this particular document into
the uh uh into the U into the token
weight pairs okay and this is this is
given by the uh neural sparse models and
these models like U either like they are
inside open search or it can be hosted
somewhere outside of open search say
like Sage maker and then as you see here
this uh token weight pairs like give
some add some semantics to your document
right for example this particular for
this particular document you see the
higher weightage is added for the words
like technology and Mac whereas uh the
uh tokens like fruit the apple fruit
froods are are are like given lower
weights right so that is the way it add
semantics so that it is able to
differentiate the
apple fruit versus the Apple technology
right so you get this automatically from
your Spar encoding processor and you add
these features and and then and then
they get injested into the open search
inverted index and then on the query
side you have this uh open search query
type called neural Spar query which will
do this conversion again for your uh
incoming query right so for example here
for the Apple headphones neural SP query
will talk to the farar enoda model and
then convert that into vectors and then
do that dot product against the document
uh
features in addition to this you can
also add uh the search pip plane for the
for your neural spur query with the
sparse two-phase processor this is one
of the uh recent uh feature that our
service team added so here basically
what happens is your uh the neural
neural Spar search happens in two phases
so basically first uh there will be a
threshold that is like an input from you
as input parameter from you say you say
okay only uh uh only uh the documents
top documents by matching the tokens
here uh whose weights are greater than
equal to 0.5 for example and then you
retrieve the documents based upon this
particular filter and then and then
rerank those documents only with uh with
all the tokens considered even the lower
weight tokens so this way you this way
you could even you could reduce the
number of dot products that's happening
uh like uh instead of considering the
all list of tokens it will be just doing
the dot product retrieve the documents
based upon the token weights with
greater than 0.5 so you are basically
trying to reduce the dot product but
still considering the lower uh weight
tokens only on the ranking phase this is
one of the improvements that is giving
better results than the version one
neural SP
search so not not only on the uh search
s but but also with respect to the
models uh like last year we had this
open search spots models V1 released uh
version one and uh and we had like three
variants of models again and like the
one of the one of the one of the
challenges I would say with with those
models was like the size the number of
parameters that these models were
trained with they were like decent in
quality but because of the size of those
models uh the injection throughput and
the search latency metrics were uh were
like facing some challenges so recently
last month we had uh this open sech SP
models V2 released and these models like
the size of these models have
drastically reduced in the number of
parameters because these models were uh
trained by the knowledge distillation
process having the teacher student model
training approach and as a result we got
three uh uh models again uh the distal
version one the first one is the buy
encoder where you use it for both the
queries and documents and the second one
is the document only digital uh version
of the model which is like only for the
documents side you will you just do the
uh feature expansion for your uh
documents then for the queries you don't
do
it and we also have this mini version of
the first two models to even improv
slateny but uh uh but with the trade-off
in accuracy so all these models are open
sourced uh and available in hugging
phase at this particular
link so on The Benchmark side like uh
there was there was like experiment
conducted to see what is the performance
of these models compared to the spars
models V1 uh version one and and there
was like uh uh the injection through
puts search latency uh we got
improvements in these metrics without
compromising anything on relevance
because the ndcg at 10 on the beer data
set was calculated and it was
approximately same for the uh Spar
models V1 and the sparse models version
two so uh yeah the now the models are
reduced in size without any compromise
in relevance improving your throughput
and latency metrix and the details of
that particular Benchmark is in this
link
okay so on the uh uh dense search so
here we have the injust pipeline uh text
process with text or text image
embedding processor based upon the
multimodel natur of your documents
basically use this processor to convert
your uh uh documents multimodel
documents uh into vectors uh with the by
talking to the uh dense embedding model
sitting in say like into open search or
outside open search and then on the
query side again you have your
multimodel query you use neural query
which is going to convert this
particular multimodel document into one
single Vector
representation and and finally uh you
hit the KNN search to get the results
automatically so like most of the things
are done within open search you don't
have to do it on the application site
and this link uh takes you to the
complete notebook uh which which takes
you through the process of fine-tuning
the embedding models because as as we as
we learned enough that fine-tuning
Vector embedding models is going to
perform well instead of using H the
Shelf hugging phase or uh open source
embedding model so uh like in in this
particular notebook we have a we first
have a fine-tuned llm which is used to
generate synthetic coers like the
triplets and this triplets are used to
uh train a uh train a sentence I mean
find tune a sentence Transformer and
then that would that would give you the
uh a fine-tuned uh embedding model that
you could put inside uh open search or
post it somewhere outside open search so
this takes you to the the detailed
process of how to fine-tune the vector
embedding models for your domain
terminology yeah the next is hybrid
search uh which is getting more popular
so you you do different uh types of
scoring for example here by bm25 scoring
k k and scoring and then you normalize
the score separately and then you
combine the scores uh Say by using a
weightage for example you want to have
0.3% of keyword search score and 0.7% of
your question similarity score and then
you rank your documents based upon the
new com combination of scores so this
this is in general all the steps for
hybrid query but hybrid search so with
open search search pipeline
normalization processor you have to just
like uh tell what is the weightage that
you want to tune and what is the
combination normalization technique that
you want to use and then that's it like
so you just use a hybrid class and then
you apply this search pip plane then
everything is taken care by open search
itself so you don't have to do this uh
uh list of steps that is listed
here the last search type the
conversational search here like as you
know to build a conversational Search
application say a chat board uh there is
a lot of moving parts right like first
you have a question and then you have to
convert that into embedding model uh
then perform KNN search or any other
different any other uh retrieval that
you interested in and then you get the
documents in addition to those toet
documents you also have to look up is
there any history of conversations that
is related to this new question then you
have to also include those documents
that happened in the previous
conversation and then you find tune your
prompt and send it to large language
model for it to throw in response and
this is going to happen for every uh uh
turn of conversation uh with the user
right so with the rack processor search
pipeline this is all abstracted from the
developer so you just have to do it uh
configure everything in the rack
processor once and open search will be
able to just do all these steps listed
here even even looking up the memory
index to store the history of
conversations and do that
automatically so yeah so we talked
enough about result reranking which is
the last phase uh uh in this uh search
life cycle and yeah like the popular
approach the cross encoder using the
cross encoder models to R rank your
results yeah like we have uh in open
search we have this uh search PIP plan
with the rank processor which is going
to do with this automatically for you
which is retrieving the documents
talking to the Cress Cod model get the
new scores rerank the documents and then
throw the rerank documents out so you
just have to use the rerank Clause along
with the main query and with the with
the search pipeline it's going to do it
automatically like by talking to the
model wherever it is
sitting okay so yeah so we had multiple
examples today on using judgments to uh
train your custom models that could be
used at the Retriever and the ranking
phase uh so first like to to get your
judgments one of the straightforward
approaches is using explicit feedback
right say you have your search team or
your uh group of people who's going to
annotate your popular queries as uh
relevant and non-relevant and then you
can use that subset of human annotated
uh set to train a large to F tune a
large language model so that this large
language model will be knowing to uh
evaluate your uh popular queries telling
that's relevant and non-relevant or even
graded graded labels and then you can
use this combination to uh to Dera your
judgments directly but still like this
involves uh aspects of cost and also
scaling right like uh human and also the
fine-tuning large language model might
get uh uh might get complex so that's
where like we have uh the uh getting the
implicit signals from your application
like based upon user interactions uh
captured through open search uba so open
search uba is going to have these two
different indices like uh our colleague
ashat mean dived into details this
morning but yeah you have your
application you have your plug-in in the
uh application site and then it's going
to throw out all the uh events and
queries and then you're going to log it
into two separate indices in open search
and then you have your implicit signals
converted to judgments once you have
your judgments then you can think about
uh training Uh custom models both on the
both for your Retriever and the re
ranker for example like for uh on the
retriever side you can have uh you can
have a training for uh learning to boost
model which we are currently
experimenting so uh basically this uh
learning to boost model will will throw
you out
weights terms of like what what what
weightage of lexical search and what
weightage of uh Vector search could be
uh could be a good uh uh combination for
this new query so basically it's like um
you're dynamically selecting retriever
retriever type because we covered you
know like there are different search
types right so we have this LTB model
throughout to throw out the right
weights for your hybrid search and then
you do the dynamic retriever selection
and then use that Dynamic retriever uh
dynamically selected retriever as for
the online
search and on the uh reranking uh side
we we can either use learning to rank
model or personalize to be trained from
those judgments and then have this uh re
code results out of these uh models and
one thing one advantage here is that you
can use open source re ranking plugins
because we have Amazon personalize uh
and LTR model strictly I mean uh tightly
integrated with open search reranking
pipelines so with that uh I will give uh
give it to haer for a quick demo on the
conversational search with open search
all right
so we have few minutes um we go to
conversational search demo and um then
if you are interested we can demonstrate
how to rewrite the queries using llms I
think we we only have three minutes left
um all right so here we are using Dev
Tools in open search dashboard uh to
create the conversational search using
the uh rack Rack processor in search p
so the first step would be to enable the
settings of the cluster to enable the
memory
feature that will uh store the
conversational history uh of your uh of
your user so the question and the uh
responses and we also enable The Rock
pipeline Next Step would be to create
the injust pipeline so the injust
pipeline as you see here we are actually
creating text embeddings from our data
um so so we have the model ID there that
is hosted in Amazon bedrock in our use
case and then we map the original text
text content into the uh field that will
host the embeddings called text content
embedding next we need to create the uh
index yeah I think I already have it
there so let's delete it
first so the index here are something to
be aware of so we enable in the setting
uh the index of type Canon of course and
we also say that we want to use the ml
injust pipeline that we just created in
order to generate the embeddings at
injust time whenever we have new
documents and then in in your mapping so
you have your original text field and
then you have the Cann Vector type of
field to host the embeddings so quickly
we'll adjust some data samples so this
data is um actually we captured some
data regarding the different search
types that are supported in open search
uh and we'll ask some questions
regarding that um so an example of how a
document looks like so I just ingested
the doc the text document right and we
see here in one example of a document we
have the original text and we have the
generated
embedding now in order to run the uh
conversational search we mentioned that
we need the SE pipeline so here we
create a ro pipeline we Define the
processor of type retrieval augmented
generation processor we Define the model
ID or set the model ID which is the llm
uh in our use case and we Define the
system prompt user instructions um that
you can um customize basically uh for
your prompt engineering so I created the
the search pipeline now I create a query
a memory that will host the uh
conversational history I will take
this memory ID so I can use it later now
we'll have we'll start with one question
so here is the search query at search
time we include the search pipeline we
mentioned that we would like to use the
rock pipeline at search time and then we
are using neural query to run similarity
search uh using the text embeddings uh
we Define the same embedding model at
search time as well to generate the
embeddings of the text and then we call
the processor generative um rug
processor with the different parameters
including the llm model memory ID
context side message message size and
timeout these uh settings are regarding
like how much of messages or like text
question and answer would like to store
in our memory so I copi the memory ID
earlier let me paste it
here and the first first question will
be what is neural Spar search with open
search here we are using an old old
version of a clo to run this experiment
so bear with us takes some
time
um and here we see the generated answer
so we have the hits we have the context
and we have the generated answer from
the llm under the retriever augmented
generation processor with the message ID
that we'll see later in the memory so we
see based on the search results with is
the context neuros Spar search is an
open search alternative to semantic
search the rest of the um generation now
the second query will be a follow-up
query how is it different from semantic
search so here we expect the llm to
understand that we are talking
about if you're following neural Spar
search uh let me copy the same memory
here and we'll run the followup
query and then we'll check the
conversational history for that memory
ID which let me update from
now okay checking the results let's hide
the hits and now from the retriev
augmented generation generated answer we
see that it understood that we're
talking about neur our search and here
it explains the differences are both
neural search methods and open search
that aims to improve the uh search
relevance and using the memory feature
indeed this is how we were uh able to
ask this follow-up question and you can
customize basically the memory settings
how much messages you would like to keep
and now we can check also the different
uh messages query and um question
question and answer then generated um
asked by the user uh using that memory
information so this is how in few API
calls in Def tools you were able to
build a conversational search with open
search um I think we're on time okay um
so thank you
everyone um and wish you a good continue
Stu
thank you a thank you Prine questions
from the
audience
there sorry for making it hard for you
uh so this question is about uh the
cache we talked about the cash which
helped you get your latency down from 3
seconds to 600 Mill seconds it's a
technical question what if it's a not
exact match of the query but it's very
similar to the query how do you decide
uh to retrieve a similar query which is
not an exact
match from the query which the user
typed from your KNN index of course yeah
so so yeah so first of all but for
having the semantic cach like we you
should think about considering all your
popular queries so you know right so
what is is going to be your most used
queries most frequent queries from your
search log so that should be your first
uh way of like hitting the llms and
storing them as cash so coming to this
second point where like okay so first
you do the exact match and something is
not matching so and then what you have
like based upon uh say the the match is
not happening in the exact search exact
lexical search and then you do the
similarity search but for this
similarity search say you are seeing
whether there are like any
more more similar queries for this
particular query so that I can I don't
have to hit my llm again and then
retrieve and then just retrieve the
already extracted filters from the
memory for this case like you you should
you should experiment with proper
threshold values what is going to be the
threshold value so that you consider
this is going to be a uh uh probably uh
already I mean probably a good similar
query that you could that that that you
could derive directly from the cache
instead of going to the lam so
experimentation on that particular uh
threshold is where you decide okay
whether I whether I'm going to use this
uh uh query from us this result from the
semantic search or am I going to go to
the llm directly again for the another
hit and then store it back to the
semantic cash so so yeah it all starts
with the popular queries and based upon
that you learn your threshold values and
set your threshold values to see whether
to hit the llm or use that particular
thing from your from your can and
index okay we have a question from uh
matush uh he's interested in the U your
experience with latency of the search I
think 600 milliseconds uh were mentioned
and he was wondering if that is the
latency that your customers toally face
or what these 600 milliseconds were
relating to no that was uh related to
our experiment so we are not really
building all best practices there uh so
in our experiment we did basic uh
indexing and search we hit three seconds
and then with this caching we were able
to reduce to 600 millisecond but you can
definitely go uh lower than that if we
uh review all the best practices that
you need to implement for search latency
uh yeah just to add that that c 600
milliseconds came from that is the like
when there is a similarity search first
it it does an exact search it there is
no match and then it goes to the
similarity search passes the threshold
and then the result is out so that's
where that 600 milliseconds 3 3 seconds
was down to 600 milliseconds but if
there is exact match then it's going to
be even down even belowed from that
three 600 millisecond and again this is
on the CPU setting for our data set
samples like for our for our demo data
set yeah so that was basically on a on a
demo experiment
stuff thank you for a good talk um you
you showed us you know like an
architecture of the whole thing which is
quite standard you know query
understanding retrieval
rerank uh I'm wondering how uh how much
of uh this experiment is feeding into
the dog food for uh Ubi yeah so for
example uh if you think of such a system
usually you know there will be different
stakeholders who are responsible for
optimizing uh query understanding there
could be different and there could be
some overlap like you know optimizing
query understanding quality optimizing
retriever you know latency and quality
optimizing reranking and and so on uh
how much of
the uh so for example in today's uh
earlier talk about Ubi I didn't see much
of the you know the internal bit the
interfaces between the query
understanding and retriever for example
or the Retriever and the ranker the the
information the signals the uh you know
what these system subsystems work on uh
how are they capturable in the schema
that Ubi is building and are you guys
feeding into that okay so uh I can I can
just talk about that retriever part for
example uh the schema whatever uh mean
morning you saw that's the standard one
but say like for for you if you want to
build a model that you want to use it in
your uh retriever s for example like a
learning to boost model and then for
this like what we trying to do now is
like take the queries whatever is stored
in your query index and then see if that
wasn't that that was a hybrid search
where you have multiple queries in that
and and and and understand what was the
weightage used there so that that's all
like you do like you you understand what
should be done from there and then you
take the queries you do the processing
you do the sort of building the training
data set from that particular query
index so it's not something like you get
get R rade for your for your schema it's
like you you decide okay I want to have
a learning to boost model so let me see
what are the what are the weights in
different fields but the waits in
different different subqueries that in
the same query and then you train a
model so it's like this this is like you
based upon your requirements you take
that and then do the further processing
and then based upon that further
processing you project that data as
features into the uh uh into the model
so it's just the same so you you you do
the further processing from those
queries and events especially queries on
the retriever side for a learning to
boost model in
case okay thank you very much I think
we're at time um we have one we have
more questions plus uh so please
approach um AR and Prine directly um
yeah thank you very much for your talk
thank you